<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Kupp</title><description>Kupp</description><link>https://your-website-url.com</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:13:22 +0200</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:13:22 +0200</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://your-website-url.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://your-website-url.com/blog/first-post</guid><title>Bioavailability</title><description>A description of my first post.</description><link>https://your-website-url.com/blog/first-post</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 22:01:00 +0200</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Bioavailability</h1><p>I talked about bioavailability in another article, but not that profoundly. Let me give you an example on this: You'd like to increase muscle mass because you want to look like someone that could tame a bear with his fist or something.</p><p>What do you need to know? Our body's cells are halfway made up of protein, which is built up of dozens and dozens of amino acids.</p><p>Now back to muscle mass. The muscles in all human bodies share the composition of amino acids they are built up of. So to increase that mass, you need to absorb more or less exactly that composition of aminos in your diet. So the more that dietary composition resembles the composition of your muscle mass, the higher the bioavailability.</p><p>So what does that mean now? Suppose the composition of aminos found in beef is only about 80% the same as in your muscle mass. That implies that you'll only be able to use these 80% to fix broken fibers in your muscles. So you consume about 100 grams of protein in a steak but only 80 grams could be used to be built into your muscle.</p><p>But bioavailability in fact is the actual availability of nutrients in our food. You can optimize the composition based on what you want to get up to. But after all, you can't just eat a perfect amino combo and wholly use it to build muscle, it doesn't work like that. There's loads of stuff going on in your body and it gets itself what it needs.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>